<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Moetes</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Moetes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:56:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moetes Development Environment</title><link>/blog/moetes-development-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:56:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/moetes-development-environment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Setting up a development environment is crucial for efficiently creating and testing hardware products. At Moetes, we follow a structured approach to ensure our developers have the right tools and configurations to streamline the development process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="choose-the-right-platform">Choose the Right Platform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Selecting the appropriate platform is the first step. We typically use platforms like CircuitPython, Arduino, MicroPython, Raspberry Pi or custom development boards depending on the project requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will formally support the following platforms:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with IoT Development</title><link>/blog/getting-started-iot-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/getting-started-iot-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>Modern IoT development hinges on two critical pillars: robust wireless connectivity and intuitive voice integration. This guide strips away the hype to focus on architecture, protocols, and engineering best practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-iot-architecture--hardware-fundamentals">1. IoT Architecture &amp;amp; Hardware Fundamentals&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="core-layers">Core Layers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A functional IoT system operates on three distinct layers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Device Layer:&lt;/strong> Sensors capture physical data; microcontrollers (MCUs) process it; actuators execute commands.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Network Layer:&lt;/strong> Communication modules transmit data via gateways or direct internet connections.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Application Layer:&lt;/strong> Cloud or edge servers process data for user interfaces and analytics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="microcontroller-selection">Microcontroller Selection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The MCU is the engine of the device. Selection balances performance against power consumption.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>